Watch for the signs.
Silver Linings Playbook is a drama, comedy, romance
film directed by David O. Russell.
After losing his job and wife, and spending time in an institution,
a former teacher winds up living with his parents.
He wants to rebuild his life and reconcile with his wife, but his father would be
happy if he shared his obsession with the Philadelphia Eagles.
Things get complicated when he meets Tiffany Maxwell who offers to help him reconnect
with his wife if he will do something very important for her in exchange.
Pat Solatano Jr., played by Bradley Cooper.
Tiffany Maxwell, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
Pat Solatano Sr., played by Robert De Niro.
Dolores Solatano, played by Jacki Weaver.
Dr. Cliff Patel, played by Anupam Kher.
Danny McDaniels, played by Chris Tucker.
Silver Linings Playbook is a 2012 American romantic
comedy-drama film written and directed by David O.
The film is based on Matthew Quick's 2008 novel The Silver Linings Playbook.
It stars Bradley Cooper and Jennifer Lawrence, with Robert De Niro, Jacki
Weaver, Anupam Kher, and Chris Tucker in supporting roles.
The film is set in Lansdowne, Pennsylvania.
Cooper plays Patrizio "Pat" Solitano Jr., a man with bipolar disorder who is released from
a psychiatric hospital and moves in with his parents (De Niro and Weaver).
Pat is determined to restore the love of his estranged wife.
He meets a young widow, Tiffany Maxwell (Lawrence), who offers to
help him if he enters a dance competition with her.
The two become closer as they train, and Pat, his father, and Tiffany examine their
relationships with each other as they cope with their situations.
Silver Linings Playbook premiered at the 2012 Toronto International Film Festival on September 8, 2012,
and was released in the United States by The Weinstein Company on November 16, 2012.
The film opened to critical acclaim, with praise for Russell's direction
and screenplay, and the performances of Cooper and Lawrence.
It grossed $236.4 million worldwide.
A recipient of several accolades, it received eight nominations at the 85th Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director, Best Adapted
Screenplay, Best Actor, Best Supporting Actor and Supporting Actress and with Lawrence winning the Academy Award for Best Actress.
The film explores themes of depression, infidelity,
dancing, friendship, philadelphia, pennsylvania.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.